Hey everybody, this is Gautam Govindan.
This is Shamik Chakraborty.
And this is Broke Studio, the podcast with...
No edits!
Let's go.
Today we have a very special guest.
We've been trying to book him for two years.
That's why we haven't been doing the podcast.
That's what we'll say.
It's Kenny Sebastian, everybody.
Thank you for having me, guys.
Thank you for picking up the mic, which was there all this time.
Yeah, I did the mic drop before the episode starts.
That's how good it is.
That's how good it is, man.
It's pre-mic dropped, this episode.
Welcome.
Thank you so much for doing this.
Kenny Sebastian, you are a comedian.
I am a comedian.
Editor.
Director.
That's not your second career, I'm sure.
No, no.
Actually, my first career is editor.
That's where you started?
That's true.
And you started other people's work?
I used to do corporate videos in Bangalore, actually.
All the internal videos.
One early video was carpooling instruction video.
Wow.
For editing infosys.
And I had to edit and talk to people.
It was serious.
Did you do those?
Sexual harassment videos as well?
No.
I missed out on that.
I think you should tell the full term, you should say.
Prevention of sexual harassment video.
Oh, that one I've done.
I've not done the sexual harassment.
I don't think...
Oh, they're like, this guy's good with the carpool.
You know, he's ready for the next level.
Yeah.
But wait, this carpool video, it's like a serious video with employees only.
You know, when you work in a company and you see an email from your HR saying,
okay, you're the inspiration.
You're the person who's going to do the instructions for the carpool.
And then you press the link and it says, hi, building A will exit from this exit and get
into your carpool.
That video, somebody had to shoot and edit.
Oh.
And actually, to be honest, it is not like, I was very good at making uncomfortable people
comfortable on camera.
Oh.
So I used to keep getting the gig again.
So you used to shoot and edit?
Yeah.
Through end to end.
End to end.
And I used to, I used to like have this gag where I couldn't tell them it's just me.
So I used to pretend I had a team.
Yeah.
So then I used to be like, hey, I'll get back to my editing team.
And weirdly that, they took me more seriously that way.
Yeah.
That's true, dude.
That's how you learned that lesson early.
I learned it too many years in comedy.
I'm like, yeah, I only negotiate.
Yeah, negotiate.
You got to pretend like there's a team.
I mean, now I have a team.
Yeah.
Because now the manager can say that, oh, he's very unhappy.
You can't be like, I'm unhappy.
Yeah.
Exactly.
I'm very angry now.
Did you have like slightly different personas when you played your, you wore your editing
hat and your shooting hat?
No, no.
I mean, I never.
I never.
I never spoke to them as a different character.
But like, if I had a friend coming as my.
Hello.
Yeah.
Why am I trying?
I know.
They're like, they don't even suspect it's not another person.
Are we trying the action?
No, no, no.
I mean, you can try whatever.
No, no.
You are doing yourself.
So you do what you want.
No, but I had to get a second cameraman.
I just call a friend and be like, all you have to do is just make sure that red light is
on.
Okay.
So then I still be like, you know, my camera.
Camera person.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
But that's cool.
So you started working very early, right?
Yeah.
While you were studying or before?
17.
My dad.
17?
School.
17.
Yeah.
In school.
My dad had started his own company and his office building was right next to my school.
So after school, I used to just go hang out in the office and then I used to offer to
do graphic design for.
Oh, nice.
Because I was good with like basic graphic design.
Got it.
So his first workable logo for his company I made.
Okay.
My dad's very sweet.
They're like, ah, my son's making it.
Let's use it.
Did you get paid?
Uh, no, no.
My dad didn't pay.
Then I started doing a journal.
You should take this up with him, man.
Yeah, dude.
I actually felt a little bad when he asked.
I was like, fuck, dude.
Like pocket money should go up or something.
No, no.
And then I did a college journal for Christ College.
That was my first paying gig.
Nice.
And then I gave that money to my dad, dude.
And my dad took it also.
What?
He was shameless fellow.
Dude.
Dude, Christ College has given so many gigs to so many people.
And it's your first.
I mean, uh, I, there was a time when I said.
Sorry, not Christ.
St. John's Medical College.
Well, I take it back.
Nobody does gigs for St. John's.
Not me.
St. John's Medical College.
My cousin was in the college and he was also sweet.
He was like, his name is also Kevin.
And he was like, uh, oh, my cousin does, uh, graphic design.
So let's, let's get him to do it.
So I worked on for three months.
Oh.
And the lady who was organizing it was very tough.
Like tough to deal with.
So I got my initial client training.
Yeah.
From them.
So that, that was my first, I think it went four grand from it.
And I heard somewhere you're supposed to give your parents.
The first.
The first paper.
My dad took it, man.
From the parents weekly newspaper.
Yeah.
Dad, all the dad publishing.
This is like a second stream of income for the dad.
Like my son will give it.
Parents weekly.
But, uh, you, you studied.
We were talking earlier that.
Yeah.
Two classic engineers who did only engineering and all the things parents want you to do.
You want to understand the other side.
How did you convince your parents to do us?
Or maybe the logo was where he was like, okay, he needs to learn.
No, dude.
Like my dad doesn't remember this.
By the way, I, I was also on the engineering part.
I went for that entrance exam.
Yeah.
CET.
You wrote the CET.
No, I went for the coaching for CET.
Okay.
I did 11th and 12th computer science.
And then.
We saw your marks.
It's little.
Yeah.
Hey.
I did.
Distinction, bro.
Distinction.
Yeah.
I mean, yeah.
It was distinct.
Distinctly 73%.
The fuck?
What is this?
A roasting?
Sorry.
We, one of our habits is we go to LinkedIn and see what people have put there.
And I knew it was a mistake.
So I randomly, we will mention things from your.
Yeah.
But this is 70 something percent.
You were like a serious.
How do you know that I have.
I mean, that's pretty terrible.
73.
Where did you lose marks in?
You were too busy acquiring real skills with the computer.
Maths, dude.
I lost all that.
You got maths.
Yeah.
Maths.
I'm bad.
Yeah.
Like, I'll tell you one math problem.
You should.
When your dad asked for your 4,000, don't give it.
That's not the math I've learned.
You have 4,000.
Your dad asked you for 4,000.
How much do you give?
Kelly has 4,000.
His father asked for it.
How much will he have at the end?
Calculate their ages.
That's so funny.
Shit.
Dude, I didn't know my math issues translate into this also.
Oh my God.
But you did a.
So, I know you've mentioned this in other podcasts, but what did you study?
How many years course?
I made a deal with my dad.
Okay.
So, in 10th or 11th is when YouTube came to India.
Who?
YouTube.
Oh, got it.
Sorry.
My bad.
Who?
2008 or 2007.
Yeah.
And I saw like kids my age making videos.
Okay.
Like white kids.
Yeah.
And I was like, oh.
And back then, I don't know if people remember back then, there was no agency given to children.
No.
So, I was like, oh.
So, children.
Children can be allowed to shoot and edit and upload and tell stories.
So, then I was like, I want to make films.
That's it.
And when I told my dad in 11th, I'm making films.
10th standard board exams time is when I started making videos.
And my dad was like, absolutely not.
I said, dad, I want to go to Bombay.
I want to go to film school.
My dad was like, absolutely not.
Then I did more research and all famous guys were like, oh, film school sucks.
Like Spielberg is like, film school sucks.
Then I'm like, but I'll go to Bombay.
Yeah.
Then my dad was like, okay, okay.
Relax.
Let's have a deal.
He has no memory of this.
Okay.
If you get distinction in 12th, you do well in computer science, you can join any degree.
Oh.
But he said it has to be a degree.
Don't do diploma and all.
Yeah.
We all know what happens to people who do diploma.
So, I was like, any degree.
He's like, any degree.
So, I got distinction.
I said, dad, I want to do arts.
Yeah.
Because I'll have enough free time to do theater and music.
This is like the plot of an education porn.
Like, any degree.
Dude, yeah.
Any degree.
I really said any degree.
He's like, any degree.
Dude, you know what?
It paid off.
I think for O1, which we use for the US tours, you need to have a minimum bachelor's degree.
Yeah.
So, if I had not listened to my dad, I couldn't have toured with stand-up.
Oh, you mean for the visa?
Yeah.
Minimum is a bachelor's degree.
Wow, dude.
I didn't know that's where it'll come to bite you.
There are a lot of people who go to the US who I doubt have a degree.
No, O1 visa.
Like, artist visa.
Artist visa.
They don't want some random artist.
They want him to study a little bit and then...
Yeah.
They'll educate it.
So, I did four years of painting.
Painting.
In...
Go ahead.
Are you asking?
No, I'm asking.
Painting.
Is that the name in your certificate?
It's like...
Painting?
Bachelor of painting.
Bachelor of visual arts.
That's what I'm talking about.
That makes you look awesome.
Let me tell you something.
I have a theory.
The more...
No, this is maybe wrong.
But the more cool the name sounds, the more suspicious I am about that thing.
Mass communication.
It's just...
What is it?
So, I think...
Talking to overweight people?
I've...
So, when you talk to a lot of overweight people, it's mass communication.
I mean, that was my childhood interpretation.
You're saying that overweight people have a lot of mass.
Mass.
Okay.
Mass is different from weight.
It is different from weight.
Oh, you...
They taught that in visual arts?
So, physics was good.
That's what I got.
I got 85 in physics.
That's horrible.
In my house, they would have killed me.
Wait, wait.
That's honor killing, Rabin.
85?
Yeah, CBC.
It's bad?
Honor killing.
It's pretty...
How much you guys got, dude?
I got 93.
I got 99 in physics.
Okay.
I'm a physics...
I'm talking overall 93.
Yeah, same.
93 overall.
Overall?
Yeah.
And there was like a bad day at school.
And you can see this reflects in the difference in our career.
No, to be honest, I thought I could have gone to engineering college.
You're like, what's 0?
Honestly, you did the right thing because board exams...
Like, I regret how much I studied for board exams.
Yeah.
Because, like, I was like, some point in my life, they should ask me.
Even today, I feel.
Someone should ask, hey, how much you got in physics?
You're saying it didn't help at all.
I'm sure it helped with the college.
It helps with confidence.
It helped me with confidence.
No.
College, it helps.
Getting to college helps.
Yeah, right?
Yeah.
And then, I mean, like, but college didn't help overall.
I think it's a double-edged sword because people in college were like, where is that 99 physics
pain?
You really got 99 in physics?
I got really good 99.
Damn, bro.
Yeah, that's my...
And I peaked early.
Oh.
But, you know, I'm so glad I did computer science, dude.
Like, a lot of...
72 is not doing computer science, dude.
Stop it.
You're like, you dropped out.
You know what?
It's okay, bro.
Vulnerability is the new punk rock.
You dropped out, like, before only.
Yeah.
You did the Bill Gates thing before.
Well, okay, let me reframe it.
When I went to the painting college, they were like, why are you here?
Why are you here?
Yeah.
You should have gone to engineering.
I understood.
Yeah.
I'm overqualified.
Bro, this, you know what?
I once did this GRE coaching I went for.
And they do a...
What do you call it?
Like, a diagnostic test.
As if there's a medical profession.
They call it that.
To see where you stand before the coaching.
Yeah.
And I scored so high.
They put me up.
They're like, you're the highest ever scorer.
The teacher was like, bro, you teach me.
Are you serious?
And then, with that confidence, I signed up.
Slowly, my grades went down.
I did the whole course.
By the end, three guys had beaten me, dude.
And they're like, what happened to that?
No education.
So, I think this...
Me feeling like...
I didn't get good marks.
Maybe motivated me to work really hard.
True.
Maybe is that.
You're right.
On the other hand, I just took a nap after my 99.
No, same thing for me.
IIT coaching...
Dude.
Like, I was like, acing it at the coaching center.
And then, my parents came to just check on my progress.
And I was listening.
And so, they were like, you know, go away.
Let me tell the truth to your parents.
My prof...
My prof was like, he's a genius.
Oh.
He's an unbelievable...
I heard all of that.
And I was like, what a guy I am.
Yeah.
And then, I...
I mean...
I've bombed so hard.
Listen, relax.
We know what you did after that.
I don't know if you know this guy.
What he did?
He's the...
This guy is...
He got the highest in the CAT percentile of his year on...
Not highest.
Whatever.
Top four.
Yeah.
I mean...
Whatever.
Yeah.
Dude, he's 99...
99.99999 something percentile, this guy is.
What is math numbers is like making me sick, dude.
Can we get you something to paint?
Whatever.
Yeah.
I just need to...
No, but so...
In painting schools, how long...
How long is this course?
Is it a four-year course?
Four-year, yeah.
And what are the subjects?
So, for the first year, you do all...
It's kind of like a medical degree.
You do...
Painting.
You paint a liver.
You do painting.
You do graphic design.
You do sculpture.
And you do...
Artistry.
Okay.
Oh, then you choose your electives.
Yeah.
You choose your specialization from second year onwards.
And you can choose a minor as well.
What did you do?
Not a child.
All right.
A subject.
Yeah.
So, I choose painting.
Painting as my major.
And sculpture as my minor.
Holy shit.
Those are the big...
Like, those are the...
Yeah, top ones.
The top ones.
That's like the neuroscience of painting.
Yeah.
I mean, again, I don't know if you're fucking or not.
But I think it fundamentally...
Like, it set the foundation of...
Like, strengthening the neural pathways for...
If I have an idea in my head, I can recreate it in the real world.
Nice.
That...
Just strengthen that and it reflected into everything.
Like, if you can see a face in your head and you can sculpt it...
If you see, like, an image in your head and you can draw it...
Then, like, writing an idea is so much easier faithfully.
Like...
And it's kind of insane, dude.
Like, isn't it?
I feel it's kind of insane that if your human brain can think of something...
But you can't recreate it.
Yeah.
Your brain...
Your hand doesn't have...
It's so bizarre to me that...
We all should be taught that, I feel.
I agree.
Dude, we're losing...
Forget drawing.
We're losing the skill of writing.
I mean...
Because you barely write, right?
Yeah.
I only write stand-up sometimes now.
I...
Otherwise, I'm typing or I'm just jotting it down on the phone.
Yeah, I think it really...
Something happens.
You have a sign after a long time and you're like, who is this guy?
Yeah, I'm like, this is for...
Who is this?
Dude, when you go to the bank to fill up that form for the check, my hand is raining, dude.
When you see a pen tied to a chair...
Yeah.
This pen is committed for life to this building.
That pen is, like, abused, dude.
Yeah, yeah.
Oh, God.
And then, I always...
Those four different colored booklets are...
Yeah.
They're blue color, one white color.
I always ask.
Just...
Just to piss off the...
Dude, that watchman is doing all the work.
Yeah.
Dude.
Generalist.
Above and beyond.
He's doing everything.
Everything, like, ahead of the cage, he's doing.
Behind the cage, like...
He can slowly just open a branch outside and be like, come to me.
And he's holding that gun the whole time.
Yeah.
And you're like, okay.
Lego gun.
I'm like, how many days before you use this to rob this bank you work in?
Yeah.
But you guys ever see that guy with the gun outside the bank and you feel like, if a robbery
happened...
Yeah.
We're not safe with that gun.
Dude, it looks like a pellet gun.
Dude, if you see, I feel in terms of...
I had a bitter thought.
It's like in hierarchy of security guards.
The bank, they don't look like they can, as you said.
Yeah.
You go to a jewelry shop, bro.
Oh, yeah.
They'll punch the shit out of you.
Jewelry shop, you feel like there are undercover people also.
Yeah.
There are some people, like, it's muscles in the person showing.
It's like in the American movies, the US march.
Yeah, US march.
They're flying plane clothes.
Yeah.
Anything happens, one guy comes and taps.
And, like, even if you pass by that guy...
The guy in the chair just stares at you, like...
Yeah.
You wanna go, bro?
They sort of evaluate you from the moment you're walking in.
Yeah.
But the hospitality in, like, a jewelry shop is awesome.
And you go with, like, parents.
Oh, you just have three juices.
Yeah.
Hey, have you gone through this, Govind?
Have you gone through this?
Yeah, yeah.
He's Gautam, by the way.
Oh, sorry.
Yeah.
His last name is Gautam.
But it's...
But, I mean, everyone calls you...
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry about the computer science thing, man.
I'm really sorry.
This is damn funny.
Indian bomb.
Bombay, everyone calls him Govind.
Yeah.
And he doesn't correct them.
By the way, to be fair, just to get some brownie points, I'm the only one who pronounces
your name correctly.
Yeah.
It's Shamik, not Shamik.
That doesn't matter.
I don't care.
You know what?
That doesn't...
He's Govind, bro.
He's Govind.
These are not transferable air miles.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
We don't share our feelings.
Brownie points.
But his dad's name is Govind.
So, you are addressing his father.
Yeah, my dad's name is Govind Menon.
I actually referred to your dad.
Yeah.
Well, surprise.
I'm kidding.
Wow.
That would be the craziest thing.
How do you feel?
Top four in the country.
He's doing podcasts.
Like top 20.
And now, this is going to be top four podcasts in India.
Hell yeah, bro.
By the time this comes out.
I mean, on a side note, I feel like sometimes I see comments and people are like, a lot
of engineers who didn't succeed got into comedy.
And I'm like, it's actually the complete opposite.
I think the overachieving, really smart engineers get into comedy.
So, yeah.
Let's go with that.
This is praising you, man.
That's true.
Too late.
It's like, this guy, they come to watch a show just because, like, people bring their
parents.
Because parents will be proud of him at least.
99.9%.
They're like, you see this guy?
Yeah, 99.9%.
Like, isn't it like a thing?
Like, every high-paying engineer left their job and got into comedy.
Like, Biswa, Karan.
All the IITians.
A lot of IITians.
That's true.
But now, every IITian does comedy.
Like, it's a side profession.
Yeah, they have a comedy club.
Yeah.
All IITs have a comedy club inside the IIT.
Dude, I was running late for a show in IIT Bombay.
And I said, I'm going to be one and a half hours.
Like, just pure standstill traffic.
One and a half hours late.
And it's a competition inside IIT for stand-up.
So, 20 comics have participated.
Dude, this is how I did stand-up for the first time.
No, but it's a cultural fest.
This is intra-IIT.
No, this is intra.
Intra-IIT.
And they're like, 20 comics and then you'll close.
And I'm running really late.
I was panicking.
They're like, don't worry.
Come whenever.
They had 20 more waiting.
40 comics went up on stage.
And then I went.
I'm like, I don't think they need any more comedy right now.
But I did the comedy.
Yeah, it was good.
It was decent.
Okay.
Not great.
It was alright.
But that's how big it is now.
That's the thing.
I mean, when we started, it was like 13, 14 years ago.
But all of those people now know it's a viable thing to do.
So, like, they have had 10 years to, like, figure it out, see, learn.
So, like, I don't know.
It's going to be cool, man.
Like, maybe five, six years from now, it's going to be like a, I don't know.
They all graduate or leave their jobs at the same time.
Yeah.
But do you think someone will catch that and make it a degree now?
And that's the other thing.
They tried in the US.
I think in my brother-in-law Warren's college, the minors were like, he did a, what is it
called?
Elective, it's called?
Yeah.
He did an elective on comedy writing for television.
It's part of his college curriculum.
That's a little more formulaic.
Yeah.
Television, comedy writing.
I think a formulaic.
Yeah.
That will come.
That's true.
There is that.
But, so, what is your final project when you graduated?
Is there a project?
Yeah.
Not in this, in your final sculpture.
The format is, because I did painting, yeah.
Sculpture has a semester and exam where they give you, an actual person sits and you have
to sculpt their face.
And painting, I have, you kind of have to submit at least 20 to 30 works of art, which
is actually not much.
Oh, okay.
Because it's over six months.
Okay.
So, like, it's not a lot.
And, I was a very fast painter.
So, like, I could paint quickly.
Like, this gives a week to do one thing.
Yeah.
I was to finish in Monday and Tuesday.
And then I suggest do theater.
And you liked it.
You liked it.
I loved it.
I think it's funny.
You know, like, it's even Karan and I were talking about this.
I think the best stability I got as an artist was going through art college.
Because all these like interdynamics that comics are struggling with, I kind of went
through that in art college.
Like, the whole sell out, your true artist, volume, quality over quantity, all of that
I went through at the most fundamental level.
At college level only, that's a big conversation.
Yeah.
So, I had that journey.
So, when I graduated, I kind of knew what I wanted to do and what makes me happy.
But like, unfortunately, in stand-up comedy, it takes longer to figure out.
True.
So, like, there was one artist who I said 20.
He used to submit 70.
Oh, God.
Every six months.
70.
So, they used to…
And was it good?
Were you like behind him like…
Amazing.
Okay.
Incredible.
His…
There's a thing called a key sketch, which is the draft before you…
Huh.
He had 150 key sketches and he had 70.
Oh, this is like these musicians, like unreleased…
Yeah.
Reference tracks.
They just have them.
Our classroom, we had to exhibit half the…
I'm not exactly…
Half the classroom was him.
What is he doing now?
Again, I'm not in touch with him.
So, he was terrible with social situations.
Oh, yeah.
Okay.
Very like shy, didn't speak.
And at one point, he was even struggling to pay rent.
Okay.
And that's when I realized that it's counterintuitive.
Hmm.
If you don't make money, you stop making art.
So, inherently, there's no such thing as being a sellout.
Yeah.
Because if you earn enough money…
You will create art.
And if you don't have enough money, you do the worst crime, which is stop creating art.
Correct.
Nice.
And there was another girl who used to…
Just go for it.
Yeah.
She wasn't skilled.
Horrible at it.
She used to do…
Oh, splatter.
Splatter art.
Yeah.
Sell it for 20 grand.
Oh.
In 2009.
Wow.
2010.
That's like 21k now.
Yeah.
Jackson Pollock.
And everybody used to really like despise her for it.
But I was like, none of you have the skill like her to network and sell.
Yeah.
So, she used to spend 10 minutes, make 25 grand each.
So, networking is the art that she…
No, I mean, I saw all the categories.
Yeah.
And there was another guy, his name was actually Govind, your dad's name.
Okay.
Yeah.
So, he was like, I'm going to sell this.
I'm going to sell this.
My dad has more reference than this boss.
No, bro.
He was also Gautam.
You're forgetting.
Oh, sorry.
He was Gautam.
But he came third in GAT.
He was great from the get-go.
Yeah.
From day one.
And then he did a master's in art in IIT Bombay.
Oh.
Yeah.
He didn't have any trajectory.
He was just amazing and he ended, left amazing.
There was another, many people who came bad, left bad.
Oh.
Some people just, yeah.
Some people…
Their graphs are like…
Yeah.
They grew搤
And then…
They did, yeah.
Yeah.
They had potential.
They grew.
So, I saw all of these amazing stuff in college.
Yeah.
But that's cool.
But yeah.
I mean, this is nice to hear because it seems like you enjoyed your…
your degree, actually.
Whereas, I didn't at all.
Yeah.
Same.
I owe college for me being this person because it helped me discover my creativity.
That's awesome.
And I love and that seniors like…
There's no such thing as seniors in CKP.
Like, everybody just wants to help you.
There's no ragging word.
No.
There's no ragging.
No ragging.
They kind of know.
And our ragging was painting.
They're like,
paint for half an hour.
No, sir, please.
No, please.
It's like when you go
meet another comic,
there's this shared struggle.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So everybody's like,
dude, once you graduate,
you're fucked.
That's true.
So that's where it comes from.
Yeah.
Together against the world.
Engineering is like,
we have to split up,
get our best,
best chunk of the pie.
It feels like a zero-sum game.
Correct.
Because there are like,
your companies will have
X roles.
Yeah.
And we'll have to go in.
And your grading also is
GPA, right?
Correct.
But you guys wouldn't have had...
Everything sounds like insult.
Yeah, what is grading?
Grade.
A, B.
Yeah.
And everyone, like,
there can be a possibility
that everybody is A.
No.
Okay.
They never gave A to anybody.
It's relative grading.
Relative grading.
Yeah.
But like, nobody failed.
You only fail if you didn't
bring in anything.
Yeah.
But even that also,
you can say like,
blank, that's my art.
No, no.
Your teachers are too smart.
Yeah, I paid...
It's a white...
Okay, this is a good question.
Since you've done so much of art
and you've seen art,
you go to the art gallery now.
Yeah.
There are some paintings there
which you can be like,
this is that networking girl type.
Yeah.
This is how they've got you, right?
Because I can't tell
what is good or what is bad.
It's literally like,
you know,
when I ask you a sports question,
and I'm like,
why is this guy such a big deal?
And you like,
have to sigh and be like,
bro,
you need to understand
the context
of this guy.
Okay.
So it's exactly like that
for a painting.
You're like,
what's the big deal with this?
And then I have to like,
be like,
okay,
we need to find out
what period this fellow
made this painting,
when he made it,
was art illegal at that point?
Was art movement
not supported?
Was he from a rich family?
Any overrated artists?
Like the famous ones
who they're not alive.
I think the new kind of narrative
is that all art museums
or art galleries
have become the enemy
they were trying to...
fight,
which is,
they have shut out
local artists.
It's become this rich network.
Yeah,
because then they,
is it to increase the value
of what they're holding on to
and just being like...
It just became a place
to launder money.
And then people kind of forgot
why they made the gallery
in the first place.
So now,
like if you're a street artist,
they just don't entertain you.
Dude,
I was thinking,
because you grew up in Bangalore,
I also grew up in Bangalore.
Gautam,
you moved there
after college,
right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Who's Gautam?
Sorry, Gautam.
Yes.
We'll have to,
what if the whole episode
we put your name down?
You can just do the AI thing,
make the age
and become Gautam.
Can we?
Yeah, we can do that.
But,
it's funny how we're in Bangalore,
the guys have the same trajectory.
You and I have both
in some way,
we were the
goatee guy
and then you grew your hair,
I sort of chickened out.
I grew it for a semester.
Oh, you did?
Yeah, in my driver's license.
They put it here,
right?
Yeah, yeah.
We put my hair.
We put all details.
Yeah, full.
Pan card also.
Yeah.
And then you were in a band,
of course.
Yeah.
Every Bangalore guy,
how are there so many
places and bands for guys?
Everyone was playing music, dude.
I think because like,
in college,
we could go perform
at a restaurant, dude.
Yeah.
So, I think that avenue
creates that self-fulfilling.
Avenue road,
you're talking about.
We used to buy books.
Books, right?
That's right.
Imagine naming a road avenue.
Avenue is another word
you go for
when you don't want to say road.
It's like avenue road.
Yeah, bro.
Bro,
Tarang article will come now, bro.
Oh, shit.
It's a Tarang bit.
Yo,
macha Tarang is killing.
Is it a road or avenue?
Please decide.
Sorry, Tarang,
you know,
it's only love.
Tarang, yeah, dude.
You're the best, man.
But yeah,
sorry,
why did we get here?
Avenue road,
bands.
How Bangalore,
everybody's in a band.
Yeah, everybody's in a band.
What kind of music
did you guys play in college?
We played acoustic blues.
Blues.
Blues is everyone
played blues, bro.
Everyone didn't play blues, bro.
What the hell is that?
Bro,
in my world,
like,
we had to,
all the teachers,
whoever taught us.
Yeah.
Like,
my friend taught me first
and he was like an old soul.
And he's like,
bro,
all this nowadays,
what they're listening to.
Metal veteran.
Oh, no,
that time,
I don't know,
what is it?
Backstreet Boys.
I don't know.
Metal was popular.
Yeah.
Yeah,
he was like Pink Floyd.
Rock.
Pink Floyd.
It's not blues,
but whatever.
It's rock and based on blues.
And so we used to play Pink Floyd.
For a crowd who hated,
like,
the young people,
they're like,
what is this, bro?
There's one beat
and three seconds.
Like,
we need some.
Yeah,
and sober Pink Floyd
as with that
adolescent energy.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And a 10 minute solo.
Yeah,
yeah.
Solo for 10.
Like the beginning of
School of Rock,
if you watch,
Jack Black does one
insane long solo.
Yeah.
So we used to fight over that.
I'm like,
at one point,
now I know how to solo.
I also want one.
Oh.
And he's like,
bro,
you can't solo, bro.
And then I was like,
what about this?
Yeah,
I played rhythm.
So I had the most,
technically,
rhythm guitarists should
do the most on stage
because they are free to
express themselves
because they're just
holding rhythm.
But I was just like,
you can imagine how
I would be on stage.
No,
but what is,
so I know what a lead guitarist,
bassist,
what is rhythm?
Like,
which part of the song?
Rhythm is like the guy
who's playing the chords
at the back.
Sometimes there are two guitars
you're hearing at the same time.
So one is doing the solo,
but there's another.
But not every band
has a rhythm guitarist.
No.
Sometimes the rhythm guy
has lead also.
This guy is like,
not needed.
Nothing is needed.
He's only talking like
an MBA fellow.
Yeah,
we can lay off.
Lay off.
He lay off.
This guy is like,
just a drummer.
What,
Ernst and Young guys,
like,
all right,
let's cut this guy out.
Just optimize.
Yeah.
Rhythm,
just,
you know,
they can follow the rhythm
in here.
You don't need the fucking,
those are the first guys
who get laid off.
Like,
Hotel California,
the intro is played
by the rhythm guy.
Okay.
Yeah.
And the lead is played
by the lead guitarist.
And the bass is that,
you know,
bass.
Yeah.
That I know.
That is really cool
when I found out bass.
Like,
I couldn't hear it initially.
Yeah.
But someone told me
that this is bass.
And I would like,
try to search for it
in a song.
I think bass is one
of the coolest things
because,
like,
if you've got a bassist,
you're automatically
a sort of likable person.
Yeah.
Because it's not solo friendly.
So you're working
with other people.
It is an inherently
background contributor
who's happy
for everybody.
Yeah.
Instrument.
And it's awesome.
So the person is also like that.
One motherly vibe.
Don't look at me, bro.
You do your thing.
Yeah.
You need help.
Yeah, exactly.
I'll go have one coffee
on the side.
You guys handle this.
Don't pan camera to me.
Don't give credit also.
What part of the band
do you use?
No, we use an acoustic band.
Okay.
I used to play rhythm,
sing.
Yeah.
And when he used to play
the lead or something,
I used to do the bass
and the acoustic.
But again,
I'm a very basic player.
Okay.
So you got also
corporate emphasis
when you went?
No, no.
We did.
What is that?
What is that place called
where you get
if you have the hot wings
and you finish it,
they give you a free one?
Yeah.
We planned.
Wait, this is a restaurant?
It's a restaurant.
Man, I was having
Where in?
Where in Bangalore?
In near MG Road only.
Oh, shit.
Everything is there only, bro.
Plan B.
I think it's plan B.
Wait, no.
Ice and Spice.
No, no.
Plan B.
Wings is like
Plan B came later.
On Wednesdays,
they had this
for students.
They had cheaper wings.
Even on Friday wings.
Wait, wait, wait.
Could be plan B only.
Plan B is later, right?
Yeah, much later.
The early places
were like only place
and they didn't have wings.
I got to play
B flat once
when like it
got little popular.
But I did
we did a seafood restaurant
every lunchtime
where people
used to just eat
and ignore us.
Dude,
how does that feel
compared to stand up?
Because
music you can consume
passively.
You can talk.
Yeah.
Did you ever
even then feel like
why are they not paying attention?
Yeah, yeah.
At one point,
one gag I used to do
was I used to sing a popular song
and I used to change the lyrics
and to see if they noticed.
And Anup,
who was my bandmate,
was like,
I was like,
I'll change the lyrics.
Nobody gives a fuck.
He's like,
no, bro, they're listening.
And I started changing it
and then he was like,
oh my God.
Yeah.
Again, all of this was
training, bro.
Yeah.
So true.
So when people
were listening,
finally,
I was like,
are you a lyrics guy
or a music guy?
Music guy.
You?
I don't know, dude.
Lyrics guy?
I don't know.
Definitely music.
Music.
Definitely music guy.
If it's
calling attention to it,
then I'm a lyrics guy.
You know,
some songs,
they're like,
yo, yo, yo,
fucking hear these words.
Yeah.
But like,
always been moved by,
you know,
I can't do this
passive listening of music.
Yeah, I get pulled in.
Yeah.
You know,
people like play music
to study and work.
I can't do that.
Oh, that I can't do.
Yeah.
But it's a very normal thing.
Those are that lo-fi,
all the best,
mix and all.
No, dude,
they're playing pop songs
and all.
I struggle with that.
Even with the lo-fi mix,
my attention goes to the music.
I'm like,
what is this person doing?
Yeah.
I'm like,
I just sit and I appreciate the song.
Yeah.
The work becomes background.
I need like silence to work.
No, now lyrics,
the good part is that
on YouTube comments,
you can go and like,
people will be like,
oh, wow,
look at Tool, bro.
This,
every pugnant is something.
I'm like, oh.
Yeah.
You know,
when you hear a cover
of a very,
very famous song,
you didn't know
how great the lyrics are.
That's true.
That's when you start
paying attention.
That's not true, man.
There was some,
what is that,
Gorilla song.
Feel Gooding?
Not the...
Melancholy Hill.
On Melancholy Hill.
Calling.
Melancholy Hill.
Calling back to you.
Oh, that's,
that's Arting Monkeys.
That's Arting Monkeys.
Yeah.
That song.
Dua Lipa sang it.
And I didn't know
it was such a sad song, man.
Yeah.
It's like a heartbreak.
Oh, it's a sad song?
Yeah.
And Creep also
by Radiohead.
Oh, that's like,
that is Creep, bro.
No, but like,
when someone sings it,
you're like,
this is like a tragic
Shakespearean play.
Yeah.
But it doesn't,
yeah,
if the beat is catchy,
no one cares.
The ultimate proof
is Every Breath You Take
is the famous,
it's about a stalker,
but Sting wrote that song
about a stalker.
Every breath you take,
every movie you make,
I'll be watching you.
But it's a love song
to everyone.
But he's like,
that's not what I wrote it about.
Yeah.
It's the beat.
Like Mambo No. 5.
What's that about?
About Mambo No. 5.
Nobody knows.
No one,
he's never released
the first four Mambos
because they were not
good enough.
That's what I heard.
Yeah.
Dude, that day I heard
Mambo No. 5
on some DJ
played it.
I'm like, yo,
immediately you can guess
the age of the DJ.
Yeah.
Coming to my
rant.
Go for it.
Yes.
Is when people,
you feel old, right,
when Mambo.
And then some young person
is like,
I don't know.
And I'm like, bro,
you don't know
who's old.
You're going to be old
one day,
you piece of shit.
Yeah.
Like, you're going to be
to be proud
of the fact,
the only thing you're proud of
is that you're young.
Yeah.
It's really sad.
It's sad.
But I honestly,
maybe you might not be
with me on this.
I never felt that way, dude.
I never listened to music
like, oh,
this is what's popular now.
So I should listen.
Yeah.
I always listen to old stuff.
I listen to current stuff.
Like,
even with movies,
like when I was in the US,
I remember this girl
asked me,
what's your favorite movie?
And I said,
The Godfather,
which is a very obvious one.
She's like,
that's so old.
I'm like,
that never entered my head.
Yeah.
Jurassic Park 3.
That's my favorite movie.
She said,
have you not seen Mean Girls?
that was a response
as if that's the greatest of all time.
It's a good movie.
I never had this thing
where I was like,
oh,
this person's an uncle.
Yeah.
I've always been like,
okay,
I don't know this guy.
Yeah.
But to dismiss the person
only because he's older than me
or she's older
is bizarre to me, dude.
So now I'm getting all this like,
like,
I've become a dad now.
So I post stuff
and a lot of people
are like,
sweet stuff.
But then some people are like,
oh,
you're an uncle now.
And I'm like,
how is that a bad thing?
Yeah,
it's probably.
I have a kid, dude.
Obviously,
I'm an uncle.
Also,
they don't know
when you become,
you're a father,
they don't know
how relationships work.
You're an uncle.
And there's nothing sadder
than a guy
who is aging,
trying to be young.
Yeah.
That,
that,
that's the,
yeah,
that is,
more graceful to be an uncle
rather than being like,
your boy is not sweet right now.
What comes naturally,
to be what comes naturally.
Yeah.
Basically.
And I think this applies
more to guys
because women obviously
get the,
get harder
critique for getting older.
Yeah.
But like when men
try to look young,
bro,
like it's
disgusting.
You ever see a sudden,
sudden makeover
in some guy?
Yeah.
When like,
there's like a,
the beard is like,
there's a line here.
You're like,
oh.
Dude,
I never even knew
I had this ick, bro.
The line.
You're right.
I see the line
and full body
is not meant to.
Yeah.
It's uncle body.
Beautiful line here.
Dude,
yesterday I went to get a haircut
and I,
I generally in Bangalore,
I go to
one regular,
one style.
Tony and guy.
Yeah.
No,
no.
50 rupees.
Tony.
Ronaldo,
Zayn Malik.
Yeah.
In the poster and all.
Those guys,
right?
This time I went to some salon.
These guys like,
do you want haircut from like,
whatever,
like our VP of haircutting
and
CHO
or whatever.
And I'm like,
bro,
just give regular,
regular haircut.
This guy just started like,
he's like,
your hair doesn't have mass.
Do you want it to be like this?
And I was like,
bro,
I'm 35.
I just realized
I'm paying for,
don't talk to me.
That's what I'm paying for.
Just do it.
One,
two things I'll say.
First job to be replaced by AI
is that,
bro.
That we just put one thing on
and like,
wait,
so you understand?
I'm sorry,
talking to you.
No,
no,
I'm talking,
I'm just like,
like this,
getting into talking about my hair,
what your hair is,
which type.
It makes me more uncomfortable.
I'm like,
I have this hair,
bro.
This is what I have.
You just do this,
cut from here like this
and this one you don't cut.
But you've seen in the same thing,
one guy comes
and he's like,
giving full instructions.
Yeah.
And you're like,
man,
what life?
No,
are you living?
because the thing is that,
why it's,
why I don't like them talking
is because they try to upsell.
Yeah,
that's true.
That's a business angle.
Yeah,
it is.
You don't like the bonding?
That's fine.
See,
if outside the salon,
he comes and touches my hair
and be like,
hey bro,
you don't have mask.
That's cool.
Yeah.
Maybe he's done mask communication.
If he sees your hair,
then he's like,
one second
and he calls all the other barber,
hair people,
like,
we've never seen this before.
That's cool.
But in a commercial setup,
when finally,
the end is one like,
oh,
you know,
you should try this.
This kerastase will change your life.
Yeah.
Then I don't trust you.
But bonding is fine.
Like,
they're like,
sir.
Yeah,
outside the salon,
you can do whatever.
No,
no,
while he's cutting your hair,
he's just,
he's just getting annoyed.
Yeah,
that is okay.
You can talk about other,
you can sell other products,
like non-hair products.
That's all right.
No,
not even selling.
He's just,
bonding.
But in talking also,
I'm ready to talk,
but I,
now that you're bringing this up,
my only contribution is,
I say yes,
no,
more or less.
Oh,
you don't,
you don't encourage.
They carry the conversation.
Oh.
I'm part of it because it helps them.
Be calm while they're like,
I'm okay,
I'm interacting with a human.
But I'm like,
yeah,
what to do.
What to do,
that's my most common answer.
No,
recently I have,
this,
this extroversion has come out of me,
where,
if they bring up some topic,
and I try to give off one sentence.
Yeah.
Like sometimes,
you're cutting the hair,
and he's like,
you know,
there's nothing going to change.
Yeah.
And I'm like,
okay,
you know what,
let me,
Oh,
you start a debate.
I know,
I give off like,
why do you feel like this?
Oh.
Why haven't you seen anyone change?
I give off one.
Nice.
And then they pause,
and then it's pretty cool,
dude,
like.
I think my fear is,
it's rooted in very middle class mindset,
that if the conversation becomes interesting,
he'll take longer to cut my hair.
I want to go.
I want it to be boring,
so he's like,
this guy's giving me nothing.
Chick,
chick,
chick.
That's true.
But this thing you brought up about the guys who have great hair,
but nothing else is like maintained.
That just resonated with me.
I just remember.
Oh, good clothes.
Yeah.
I saw one guy in the airport change room,
and he combed the shit out of his hair.
You know,
he had the circle,
and the normal comb,
and he was like.
Double.
You know,
everyone's looking at how much this guy's grooming.
Yeah.
And honestly,
everything else was.
Do you assume that's narcissism,
or just a lot of self-love?
It could be self-love.
It could also be rooted in some sort of something.
There's some sadness also.
Yeah.
Inadequacy,
feeling of inadequacy.
Like,
this is the money shot.
this is what they need to look at.
Distract from everything else.
But was he like well kept otherwise?
No.
No?
Just the hair.
Maybe he had a Zoom call where his face was like.
Okay.
You know,
because everyone was noticing this guy's combing.
Yeah.
Like in the airport,
nobody combs like that.
Especially when you're boarding a plane.
Yeah.
That's not the environment.
I feel it's kind of like a Maslow's Pyramid kind of thing,
dude.
It's like.
Whoa,
whoa,
whoa.
Whoa.
The top of the pyramid is the hair?
Is that what you're saying?
Man,
even when an art student tries to sound smart.
Yeah.
Knocked down.
No,
like,
I feel like in India.
Oh,
the hierarchy of needs guy.
Yeah.
Yes.
In India,
like we have not reached a stage where people have their own sense of fashion.
Like we've not given that luxury yet.
True.
But like you see,
I know this sounds like I'm being racist,
but I genuinely feel like people from the Northeast have such an incredible sense of fashion.
Yeah.
And I feel like they increase that side of culture.
It's not frowned upon.
It's like part of.
Yeah.
And the anchor is like,
you discover yourself,
be a little unique.
True.
And you see somebody like dress and you're like,
man,
it's like,
I didn't even know this is an option that you could go out.
Yeah.
And have a distinct personality.
Just by your choice.
And I'm talking about men.
Women obviously.
Dude,
I think we're all like,
I'm still on that path.
By the time I'm 75,
I'll accept that you can wear anything that you want to wear.
Yeah.
Personally.
Guys,
I've like you're saying two pants,
usually.
Yeah.
Maybe three.
Which is really like,
I wish we had more energy.
I don't know why we're so exhausted.
I think we have to invest energy in wearing clothes.
Something happens.
Immediately exhausted.
You could totally plug like a,
like a company,
now like a paid partnership with which company is your favorite?
Peter England.
Lewis Philip.
First thought was Peter England.
Yeah.
I love that name.
It's such a desperate try to fake that it's England.
And like it's in Tamil Nadu,
Peter is like a slur.
Yeah.
Is it from Tamil Nadu?
No,
but it's Arvind Mills only.
I think that it is.
I don't know.
Might as well call it foreign.
Yeah.
Good.
John.
That is so true,
dude.
Yeah.
I didn't think of it.
Peter England.
I was,
I remember that moment.
I realized it's an Indian company.
I was so hurt,
dude.
Yeah.
Even all your Alan Solly.
Alan Solly.
Van Hoysen.
Hoysen sausage.
Oh,
man.
But the ones which are American,
you are something you won't realize.
Arrow.
Yeah.
I'm like,
what is this lame?
Arrow is American.
Arrow is actually American.
Oh.
Unless I'm being fooled at another level.
Different level.
This one,
no.
Your shell company.
Bata is Italian.
Italian,
no?
Bata is Czech.
Czech,
sorry.
Yeah.
But like,
India is where they do their business.
I've never heard about Bata showroom anywhere.
Have you seen a Bata showroom elsewhere?
No.
I don't think so.
I never checked.
It's like WhatsApp,
right?
It's like WhatsApp.
They're like American.
I never checked.
Bata is where I learned that marketing,
not gimmick,
but it works.
99.
Everything ends on a,
it's not 2000,
it's 199.
Yeah.
I fall for it,
bro.
My brain's like,
this is in the lower.
Yeah.
A decade.
I asked for the one rupee back also.
Give it back.
They're like,
bro,
buy some socks or something.
299.99 paisa.
Yeah.
It just goes on.
It works,
dude.
Always change.
When I say 299.99,
I'm not thinking of 3000.
I'm thinking of 2000 only,
dude.
It's so true.
It just works.
Yeah,
it works.
This is what they teach in MBA.
All this psychological stuff.
Yeah,
but what's the dirtiest thing you've learned in MBA,
bro?
When you were reading this,
it was dirty.
No,
there's,
the price,
the thing that Apple uses,
the anchoring thing,
that is like dirty.
What is that?
They say that like iPhone,
they'll be like,
okay,
iPhone,
new iPhone will come.
They'll be like,
okay,
2GB storage is there for $599,
but you can't use 2GB.
You want,
you want some more?
Okay.
Okay,
put like 100 more dollars.
They give you an amount they know that will not be sufficient for the bro.
And you ladder yourself,
you yourself,
it's like,
you know,
taking yourself to jail types,
right?
It's so true.
That,
that feels like it won't work intuitively,
but it does work.
Once you're in the middle of that journey.
Yeah.
Now you have to pay more to,
how is this different from upselling,
anchoring?
So the thing is that like,
no,
upselling is the same only because upselling is generally like if you buy a laptop and
then they say that,
okay,
buy one laptop case also.
Okay.
That is upselling primarily,
but anchoring is basically,
if you're going to buy a Mac book,
you have to pay like whatever,
like one lack,
you have to pay,
right?
So in your head,
you're like,
okay,
I'm paying one lack for sure.
Okay.
So now should I pay 10,000 more or 20,000 more?
That in the perspective of one lack doesn't seem a lot.
So you purposely make you,
uh,
what is that thing called?
Anchor.
No,
it's a Gen Z term.
Nerf the one lack model.
Yeah.
Correct.
Yes.
So that you definitely buy the one point two lack.
You've seen Mac books.
You would have done that.
Yeah.
This is also that,
uh,
second,
cheapest brand of wine is whatever.
Yeah.
They do that in cars also.
They won't put fog lamps.
Yeah.
Base model.
Base model has three wheels.
They're like,
you want the fourth one?
Yeah.
Dude,
they shamelessly put that steel wheel,
dude.
Oh,
steel wheel.
Yeah.
Base model has steel wheel.
It doesn't have the alloy wheels.
You know that Maruti,
that old one.
Yeah.
For the captain.
For the silver looking captain.
Yeah.
They do that in the base model.
You're like,
I can't go.
At least it should have one pointy thing outside.
Like you can slash another one's tire.
Yeah.
Like the dealership makes a face if you ask a base variant.
What?
Yeah.
We don't look at that one.
It's in that room.
Yeah.
You only go take it.
Here's a key.
Do one thing.
You go home and G pay me for that car.
I don't want to look at it.
That's so true.
Yeah.
Dirty shit.
That they teach us a lot.
This reminds me of that Brian Riegel bit about refrigerators.
He's like,
what is the guy selling me?
if he was honest,
what he's saying is,
this one keeps your food cold for 600.
Yeah.
This one keeps your food cold for 800.
This one,
1000.
Keeps your food cold.
I went for a travel show and he had a great bit that I still remember.
He's like,
if all of us went on a flight and he suddenly got up.
Yeah.
And we're like,
I paid this much for my seat.
And then everybody starts getting him and telling them how much they paid for their seat.
For the same flight,
there would be a fucking riot.
Yeah.
I paid 3000.
I paid 12,000.
That's so true.
Yeah.
So it's like,
it's really messed up.
That is dynamic pricing.
That comes in.
It's like,
that's an MBA thing,
brother.
Yeah,
of course.
All MBA things.
Dude,
I mean,
see,
capitalism is what has propelled this world to this.
That is true.
We are trying to be a good side of wealth inequality.
A little socialism.
A little bit.
Bro,
with that 20 lakh fees.
Oh yeah,
IIM fees.
Yeah,
20 lakhs.
Fair.
But we had like seven lakes.
Oh.
Yeah,
inside.
Did they maintain those lakes?
Yeah,
yeah.
They were like,
this one,
monitor lizard and all came out.
Oh,
that's the sign.
I'm not a purit.
Monitor lizard.
I haven't just had mineral water.
He's monitoring.
Yeah,
monitor lizard is like,
who's absent today?
Let me write on the board.
Sorry.
I had to do it.
I had to.
But,
speaking of airports,
you had a thing which you were saying.
No,
this,
dude,
like,
this is one problem I have.
Dude,
this time also,
I came from Bangalore.
So,
one guy is there.
I always,
I don't like putting my bag in,
like,
checking in and all those things.
I want to run out.
Yeah.
As fast as possible.
So,
one,
like,
trolley I carry.
Yeah.
But somehow,
at the edge,
like,
once you give the boarding pass,
you're getting in,
one guy will be there.
Yeah.
Like,
you have to check in.
Yeah.
This bag.
Oh,
yeah,
yeah.
That,
like,
you don't like that.
Bro,
like,
I've crossed everybody.
Why are you here?
At the finish line,
you can't be like,
give the bag.
Bro,
I can't,
I can't even tell you
how,
how many times I've tried
to escape this guy.
I have,
I always.
It never works,
dude.
Many times,
I just go without eye contact,
like,
purposely,
he's not looking at me.
Yeah.
I want his bag.
Sometimes,
I look at him,
he's like,
oh,
this guy's looking at me.
No,
so you just have to say,
I say that I have power banks,
full power banks.
It's just,
it's a bag of power banks.
Live wires.
I'm selling power banks.
Yeah.
I dress up as a suitcase.
I'm like,
you put me also with the bag,
then.
I don't get separated
from my suitcase,
whatever happens.
What a giant suitcase.
I'm just,
inside the hole
with all the bags.
I have a different problem.
I go with my guitar,
you know.
Oh.
Everybody hates.
Bro,
I want to learn this.
How do you travel with guitar?
I literally,
when I moved from
Bangalore to Mumbai,
my mom is like,
take this guitar.
I don't want it in the house.
I'm like,
no,
this stays here.
You know,
that's another pet peeve I have.
Yeah.
Everybody you see in the flight,
listening to music.
How the fuck you think
that music was made, bro?
By few gentlemen.
AI.
I will listen to AI music.
Few gentlemen
who sacrificed time
and learned an instrument
and recorded it
so that you can listen to a song.
And the hate musicians get.
Yeah.
For carrying an instrument.
I mean,
you'll have double pain, right?
You'll have guitar
and camera stuff.
If any camera stuff.
Camera stuff is okay.
I think,
obviously,
it's logical that he's taking
two bag spaces
for one.
Yeah.
No,
camera,
you have to remove everything
during security also, right?
You're used to that.
I don't even get me started.
It's a bane of my,
you know,
my last special,
I didn't do music
because I just couldn't carry.
Yeah.
I was like,
I can't do this guitar thing anymore.
Dude.
Also,
it's a constant,
a guitar is a target for,
like,
people clock it
and they make,
assumptions about you
immediately.
They're like,
you're some,
yeah,
who the fuck are you?
Yeah,
big guitar guy.
Yeah.
Either you're druggy
or you're like a loser
or you're not making money.
I've literally made,
my flatmate Aman,
I mean,
I didn't make,
I told him,
you buy guitar,
I'll teach you
so that I have a guitar
to play in Bombay
because I couldn't carry one.
And you teach him?
I taught him,
but I know,
statistically,
people quit within months.
So I knew.
Dude,
this is also interesting.
It's like,
it's literally like a plateau,
like everybody tries,
and the point
where you learn guitar
is where 80% drop off happens.
And the people
who get through that,
you know,
learn it for life.
And it's like a great
analogy for like,
I think,
creative field also.
Yeah.
Where it's,
the hardest point
is where you actually
should push the most.
Yeah.
And then after that,
it becomes self-learning.
It's like,
there's a point where you're like,
it's a fork in the road
where you're like,
okay,
now I got it.
Yeah.
It's bucket list is done.
But do I now add it
into my life
or do I,
if they have just pushed
their own learn guitar
for the rest of their life?
Yeah.
But this is gave
the hardest part.
Gautam is also
classically trained.
Piano.
What?
Yeah.
Not anymore.
Hindustani.
Not Hindustani piano.
Sorry.
Who are you?
Trinity and all.
Yeah.
Which grade?
Grade four.
Okay.
Yeah.
Four, five.
What's the,
how many are there?
Eight.
But why you stopped?
Is this just two students?
It's the parents pressure.
The money.
I was,
I was a prodigy
in my design.
But they only got you
into this now.
Yeah.
They got me into this
and they got me out of this.
This is a classic
Indian parents trope.
They get you into it
and then they're like,
oh, now he's enjoying too much.
Now time to study.
Much of,
how many times
uncles have been like,
oh, art.
You did art degree,
not.
Look, he followed his passion.
Same kid you were allowed to do.
That kid is sitting like this.
Yeah.
Who only made me not for,
dude, I had this,
my family friends,
we had when my,
my friend,
he used to be really good
at drawing.
And he used to draw,
he was obsessed with Titanic.
Yeah.
So he used to keep drawing
the Titanic.
My parents were like,
see how well he draws Titanic.
Why don't you draw?
So I also drew like an idiot,
some shitty Titanic
for a year.
I don't even like this.
Why am I doing this?
Why Titanic?
I used to do Titanic.
Like different angles
of Titanic.
Yeah.
How far I'm going.
Why don't you draw like
Batman or Spiderman?
Like normal kids.
They just wanted Titanic.
Like different times
of the journey.
Like,
yeah.
Back then,
Titanic was like porn, bro.
Dude,
it was.
The naked scene,
the whole movie was.
Oh, it was not that.
No, it was tainted.
It was like,
it's dirty movie.
Dude, I slept,
in theater we had gone to watch
and I slept through
the full romance.
I woke up when the iceberg,
like iceberg woke me up.
When that,
Same as the Titanic people.
Same as the people
in the Titanic.
I was sleeping in my
suite of,
oh.
Same as the people
in the Titanic.
Dude, I love that
Dua Lipa has this song
where that,
in the video,
it's an existing joke,
but she's used it
in the video.
Which is that,
it's the Titanic disaster
from the POV of the lobsters
that are going to be cooked.
So,
they get freed
when it crashes,
they go home.
It's beautiful.
But this Titanic,
I also,
it's fascinating.
I had,
I drew this,
I used to like
infographics.
You used to draw Titanic?
Infographics.
I used to like
making infographics.
What an MBA guy, dude.
No, when I was a kid,
I used to like
making infographics
and just basically
a huge chart
and I would draw
like the night,
I have made this,
the night Titanic crash
and I would draw Titanic,
it left from
this place.
Like a comic strip.
Like a comic strip
and then when it crashed
the iceberg,
it had three holes
in the hull.
So, you did like
the most boring
comic strip ever.
Wow.
Everybody knows the ending.
But that's cool.
But where did
this motivation come from?
Where does this idea come from?
I mean,
the Titanic movie came out,
that's why.
I mean,
I was not ahead of the curve.
we were drawing boobs, bro.
Did you have one?
No, no.
One with you.
Two people.
Five kids,
they were drawing boobs
and then Gautam,
he was just like,
they could have been avoided.
He could have been avoided.
He could have just
hit the stone right.
At least the hand
on the glass.
That I remember that.
That was beautiful.
No,
the same thing.
When I tell people,
I went to art college,
like what,
drew naked girls?
Naked girls.
As if you can't draw
in whichever college you are.
In engineering college,
we do.
Yeah.
Dude,
in school,
I had this
classmate who used to draw
like naked women.
Yeah.
But way too early.
Like we were in class
five and six and all.
And we used to think
what's wrong.
There's an appropriate age.
We used to think
what's wrong with this guy.
And that age,
we were like,
yuck,
what are you doing?
We didn't know
he's ahead of the game.
Yeah.
Now,
now what is he drawing?
All these yucky things
he's doing,
I don't like it.
I'm drawing car.
Yeah.
Now,
then after two years,
I'm like,
what should be in the car?
Naked girl.
Boy,
young boys are the most
disgusting living thing.
Yeah.
For sure.
It's,
it's almost like we were,
we were that.
Yeah.
But now when you see like a group,
when I see a group of like young kids
in the audience,
I'm like,
yeah.
Oh yeah.
They are filthy.
Bro,
but tell me something.
Do you ever,
tell me something.
This happens to you
where you're like,
no way I was like that
at this age.
This happens too often to me
where I'm like,
no way when I was this age.
Like this,
a Gen Z person
was sitting in the front row
of the show
and just looking at the phone.
Yeah.
And looking at me like,
this,
like this.
And I was like,
bro,
just pay attention.
He's like,
I'm paying attention.
He was almost like,
I'm doing nothing wrong here.
I'm doing one more thing
like I always do.
You continue,
no?
Yeah.
Second screen.
I am second screen,
bro.
And I was like,
bro,
I cannot even,
I never felt that old before.
I was like,
bro,
we,
in our time,
we did one thing at a time.
I have the opposite thing
when I see a young person.
I'm like,
how are they so advanced?
Like the way they dress
and the way they talk.
Such a positive guy.
Wow, man.
Yeah.
Dumbass, dude.
Like I,
that's true.
They become like fully formed
people with personalities earlier.
Yeah.
And like,
yeah,
also,
I also was,
fifth standard,
I was also,
boobs,
I was drawing,
bro.
You were drawing boobs,
Oh,
so at least on the Titanic,
there was,
yeah,
there was something.
No,
Titanic was earlier.
Titanic was third standard.
Bro,
I was at Dubai.
I don't know,
Dubai,
I drew it.
Bro,
in fifth standard,
if you drew two round things,
I'd be like,
oh,
motor,
I'm drawing motor right now.
I mean,
fifth standard,
yeah,
the naughty things,
naughty things in fifth standard.
Yeah,
same.
Fifth standard,
sixth standard,
yeah.
Maybe.
Fifth standard,
sixth standard,
I got caught.
That's how much I was watching
fifth standard.
Yeah,
same.
Eighth standard.
My dad caught me,
dude,
very embarrassed.
No,
for me,
my principal caught me.
Principal?
Yeah.
In school,
you're watching,
bro.
No,
we were watching in,
uh,
NIT.
You know,
in a computer,
yeah,
in that computer lab,
we were watching.
Bro,
in every computer lab,
in engineering,
it's already there.
No,
I know.
So,
this was like for people
to come and study,
like,
HTML and whatever,
Java.
You were making a...
And two people were
in the side,
in the monitor to the side.
Oh,
dude,
I've never seen,
I've never seen naughty videos
with another guy.
No,
I would do it.
That's very tricky,
very tricky,
dude.
I don't know.
For me,
my first...
Because I'm like,
inherently,
you know,
this fellow has a bone,
and it's a little gay,
bro.
So,
that's the thing,
right?
I didn't know anything about that.
So,
I didn't know anything about anatomy.
I just knew that I liked
please myself.
Oh.
Till like 10th standard.
What?
Yeah,
five years of just
academic watching.
What are you saying?
Yeah.
That's...
I just,
you know...
So,
when you watched it,
you didn't feel anything?
I felt,
like,
love.
Love?
I felt love.
That's like how the Beatles...
If only this lady had a blanket.
This is how the Beatles...
She's getting cold.
I wish I could clothe her.
This is how the Beatles
used to talk about sex,
by just saying love.
I felt love.
Yeah,
no,
We know what I mean.
What love means.
Completely alright.
Are you being serious right now?
No,
I have 100%...
10th standard,
my friend told me that,
so,
how was it?
I was like,
what?
How was what?
The storyline?
Yeah.
He was like,
dude,
and then he taught me.
He taught you?
No,
no,
sorry,
I mean,
he told me that,
and I went and tried it.
Yeah.
And...
10th standard.
10th standard I tried.
Sorry,
10th standard.
No,
by 10th standard I tried for the first time.
By 10th standard I was a veteran.
So,
imagine the first few weeks.
Grizzled veteran I was.
Yeah,
I ran two...
You're doing tricks and all.
Yeah.
I ran two,
I was in Iran by two,
two stations in Iran.
Two tours.
Two tours,
yeah.
What I think of tours.
I ran two tours by then,
dude.
Oh my God,
that's so crazy,
dude.
Till 10th,
I can't imagine,
dude.
Yeah.
All my life,
dude.
So,
you were into the perverted stuff early.
Yeah,
but I didn't know what to do.
As an artist,
you just...
That's true.
You were as an auteur.
As an auteur.
Yeah.
Five years.
Five years of just watching.
And I watched like more than anybody.
And in those five years,
we were like...
Yeah,
because...
Five years a slave.
Because we don't watch it out
because there's an end at some point.
I was just going on.
You're just like,
I have no end goal.
Bro,
even in there,
if they had metrics
that went back to them,
in back,
I feel like there's one reading
which is going till the end of the video.
Yeah.
And then the next video
is clicking.
Gautam at 10th time is like,
I've finished all the porn.
Yeah.
Bro,
that's probably
if there was a concept
of porn metrics
which you could analyze.
Yeah.
You could literally look and say,
who's the consumer?
Everyone.
And then director.
Yeah.
Editor, director.
I want a Spotify rap of my thing.
Yeah.
This year.
Spotify rap
is to rap them up
at the end of the video.
Okay.
Before we let you go,
we have to do a couple of things.
No, no.
So,
we've planned all this
and all you should try it.
Yeah,
we're just yapping.
Sorry, man.
We had this idea
since it's Broke Studio,
it's a very flimsy premise,
but
call it that.
Yeah.
If there's anything
you did early in life
or even
now
where people are like,
wow,
why are you trying to save money
on this, bro?
Like anything where you're like,
let me,
there's no point spending
in this aspect of your life.
Is there anything like that?
Yeah.
It's basically with clothes.
No.
I used to do,
Bangalore it works,
where I used to
save money on clothes
by layering.
So,
at one point,
my shirt
at the first three years
gets to be the main shirt
and initially
then it goes into
the inner layer.
Yeah.
Wow.
And then,
so I buy in the new outer layer
and then it keeps like
going back.
Like a snake.
You shed in one.
Yeah.
It's a recycling snake.
No,
the third stage was
it becomes my home
sleeping.
Sure.
Okay.
So,
the first is front facing.
Front facing.
Then B2B.
Yeah,
front and
back end and then home.
B2B.
First C2C.
First C2C
and then it's B2B.
Oh,
so,
because the weather
allowed you to layer,
you're saying.
That's what you're saying.
No,
no,
I was just like,
I can't keep buying clothes,
but I can't look like,
I'm like,
not like,
trendy.
That's so true,
dude.
So then,
and the people are like,
dude,
it's okay,
you can wear the same thing again.
I was like,
oh,
that's an option.
Yeah.
So,
then now the new thing is now,
I buy,
any t-shirt,
I buy XL
or XXXL
because,
XXXL?
Okay,
XXXL.
Yeah.
And,
because now,
my entire,
Tracy,
Tracy's mom,
Tracy's dad,
Warren,
Lisa,
they all use my clothes.
Okay.
So,
then I realized,
bro,
that's a very,
yeah,
that's a proper middle class mindset.
Yeah.
So,
when they have to come home,
I'm like,
don't carry any clothes.
You can just wear my XXL
and have these big,
like,
amazing,
M&S makes amazing shorts.
Yeah.
It's very expensive,
but it is pure cotton
and it doesn't wear
and it has a beautiful elastic.
Nobody carries clothes now.
They just come home
and they just wear my t-shirts.
It's great.
Dude,
that's smart
and that's ethical also.
That's a good thing.
Yeah.
I used to always use the ethical angle
for why I'm not wearing clothes.
I'm not buying clothes.
Yeah.
I'm like,
dude,
it's wrong.
And it's not like they're compromising.
Those,
the t-shirts and the shorts
are way more comfortable
than their clothes.
Yeah.
So,
that's great.
Actually,
this reminds me,
like,
earlier,
when you buy clothes,
I used to always be like,
cheapest option.
No.
Yeah.
And,
but the concept of thread count,
TSM,
all that,
I'm like,
dude,
this is all nonsense.
I'll maintain it.
It'll wear at the same speed,
no matter what.
That goes out of the window
the moment you buy,
like,
two of those t-shirts
and you've washed it three times
and it's like,
one,
you pull that one
and then the whole thing comes out.
It's just a collar left.
There's also this problem where,
whatever clothes are washed
and they are usually put back
on the top,
right?
So,
then I use them again.
Oh,
that's so true, man.
So,
the top layer t-shirts
are wearing out
and the bottom
have never been.
Yeah.
And then,
like,
one day,
hey,
this is also there.
Yeah.
And,
really look,
be like,
okay,
this one.
That's so true.
I've had,
I've had this
where people have been
in a new shirt
and I'm like,
bro,
I've had this forever.
It shows how much
I'm cycling at the top only.
Yeah.
Once in a while,
you should,
like,
flip it,
like a mattress.
You don't have to do that.
You have to flip a mattress?
You're supposed to flip
your mattress every year.
I should,
man.
It depends on the label.
So,
some mattresses are two-way
and some mattresses are one-way.
New ones are one-way.
But all the older mattresses
are two-way.
So,
to prevent sagging
of the mattress,
you flip it.
Thanks for that.
I needed that clarification.
I need to flip something else.
Alright.
Thank you so much.
Follow Gautam and Shabik
for more blah blah.
See you.
Guys,
isn't that the main camera?
Oh,
yeah.
Follow us.
Follow,
follow guys.
Guys,
just this one also.
Follow.
Follow,
follow.
See you next time.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.